servicemagic.co.uk 2015-06-13

# ServiceMagic UK Privacy Policy

Servicemagic   
Privacy Notice for Information Collected from  
ServiceMagic Site, Emails and Communications 

This Privacy Notice is effective as of March 2014. 

This Privacy Notice describes the principles and practices that apply to the use of Personal Information (defined below) that ServiceMagic Ltd. collects from users online via the website [www.servicemagic.co.uk](http://www.servicemagic.co.uk/) and offline, such as from emails or other communications 

In summary : 

  * We will collect your personal information to provide you with the content and services that you request;
  * We may use your personal information to gain a better understanding on how to market our services to you;
  * We will not share your personal information with third parties other than our service providers, or in the course of our business with you, or in the event of a dispute, unless required by law;
  * We will take reasonable measures to ensure the security of your personal information;
  * We want you to use our services, but we do not want to annoy you. We provide numerous ways for you to limit our use of your personal information;
  * You are entitled to a transparent relationship. You will have the right to access to, and obtain correction or deletion of, personal information about you.

## Table of Contents

  1. Definitions and background
  2. Scope
  3. Consent
  4. What information do we collect and how
  5. How we use personal information
  6. With whom we share personal information
  7. Cookies and other technologies
  8. User's rights
  9. Security
  10. Limitation of liability
  11. Links to other websites
  12. Our policy towards children
  13. International transfer of information
  14. Updates and modifications
  15. Who controls your information

## 1\. Definitions and background

For ease of use of this document, certain terms have been associated with the specific meaning provided below. 

" **Consumer** " means an individual who owns or leases a home and who uses the Site or Service for identifying tradesmen. 

" **Device** " means a computer, laptop, desktop, smart phone, tablet, and any other similar equipment. 

" **Personal Information** " means information that identifies an individual or that, when combined with other information available to the data holder may allow identifying an individual with reasonable certainty. 

" **Registered User** " means a User who has provided Personal Information in order to use the Services. 

" **Site** " means and includes the Site and any affiliated microsite(s) that we operate alone or with a business partner. 

" **Service** " means the services and content provided from or through the Site, such as the ability to connect consumers seeking assistance for a home improvement, remodeling or construction project with tradesmen available to provide a quote for such projects, and perform the services requested by the consumer. 

" **Tradesman** " means an individual or company who has provided contact information in order to obtain information about home improvement projects, make proposals for these projects, and otherwise interact with consumers who are seeking tradesmen for a home improvement project, remodeling project or similar services. 

" **User** " is an individual who uses the Site or Service. A User can be a user of the Site (who merely explores and uses the Site without being a Registered User), a Registered User, or a Tradesman. 

## 2\. Scope

This Privacy Notice applies to the information that we collect or receive from Users through the Site or through telephone, correspondence, or electronic communications, newsletters, interviews, surveys, and similar interaction. Any other issue not mentioned in this Privacy Notice will be governed by reference by the Terms of Service, to which this Privacy Notice is an integral part. 

## 3\. Consent

By using our Site, you consent to the processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Notice. Your continued use of the Site, or continued interaction with us, after we have notified you of a material change in our Privacy Notice will be deemed an acceptance of these new terms. 

## 4\. What information do we collect and how

  * If you become a Registered User\- We require Users to submit contact information if they wish to make a Service request, receive our newsletter or other information. In this case, the User becomes a "Registered User." 
  * If you become a Tradesman\- We require Users to submit Personal Information such as company name, name, phone number, email address, postal code, and credit/debit card number if they wish to become a registered Tradesman. In this case, the User becomes a "Tradesman." 
  * When you complete a form\- We receive and store any Personal Information that Users enter on our Site or provide to us otherwise. For example when you fill out a form to ask for information or request a Service, you may be asked to provide your first and last name, telephone number, postal and/or email addresses and your needs or interests. 
  * If you contact us\- We may keep a record of your contact information and correspondence, the purpose of your contacting us, and our interaction with you if you regarding your contact with us. 
  * If you visit our site \- We collect certain aggregate and non-Personal Information when you visit our Site. This information is automatically provided by your browser and does not relate any Information to a single identifiable visitor. This may include device information (such as type of device, operating system version, unique device identifier, browser type and language, access times, referring website addresses version, and mobile network information) or log information (such as IP address, screen resolution, and referring domain). 
  * Aggregate informationWe aggregate information, such as information about online activity, the web pages visited, the search terms used, and any link or advertisements on which Users click. This information helps us tailor our Site to our Users. 
  * Other sources\- We also may obtain Information from our affiliated entities, business partners, publicly available databases, other independent third-party sources and add it to our contact database for marketing and sales purposes to combine it with other information that we have collected or obtained otherwise. This may include phone number, email address, name, or company. 

## 5\. How we use Personal Information

Our primary goal in collecting Personal Information is to provide you with the Services offered by our Site. In addition, we collect Personal Information to gain a better understanding of individuals who are interested in our Services, so that we can find more efficient and effective ways to respond to their questions and inquiries, and to market our Services to them. The more we know about your goals and interests as they relate to our Service, the better we can anticipate your needs and communicate with you in a productive and enjoyable manner. This interaction may occur in several different ways: 

  * All Users We use Personal Information to provide our Users with access to our Site and information about our Services. We may also use Personal Information about our Users to communicate with them, respond to their questions, or as otherwise described at the point of collection of information. 
  * Registered UsersIf you have registered on our Site, we will use the information that you provide in order to give you access to the special Service that you requested. We will assume that you are interested in our Services, and may send you periodically additional information and news. You have the right to opt-out from receiving any future communications. See our User's rights Section. 
  * TradesmenIf you are registered as a Tradesman, we may use your contact information to provide access to the relevant Service, and send you service requests made by Users. We also may use Personal Information to manage your Tradesman account. 
  * CorrespondenceWe may use your correspondence, contact information, email address, and any information that you provide in your messages, to respond to you. 
  * Marketing and business developmentWe may use your contact details to request feedback from you, which could include the use of surveys. We may also use your Personal Information to estimate how likely you might be to use the Site, in order to send you marketing communications and promotional material, or to provide you with information about our other Services. 
  * InvestigationsWe may use Personal Information to prevent or investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities, or to enforce our Website Terms and Conditions. 
  * AnalyticsWe may aggregate Personal Information and usage data in order to obtain statistical information, such as to calculate the percentage of Users who have a particular postal code or telephone area code. We also use aggregated information to understand how our Site is used, for research or Service development, for example, to measure interest in, or monitor the use of any content or Services that we provide through the Site, to improve these content or Services, and for the technical administration of the Site. 

## 7\. Cookies and other technologies

We use cookies and other technologies to gather information about the Users of our Site and the recipients or readers of our communications, in order to know what information is or might be of interest to them. All Personal Information collected through cookies is processed in accordance with our Cookie Disclosure posted in the legal notices section of our Site. 

A cookie is a small file of information, letters and number, that our Site may transfer directly to your browser and then is stored on your browser, subject to the options resulting from the cookie setting of your browser. The cookie is then returned to our Site when you return on our Site. Cookies allow the Site to recognize the User's Device. 

There are different types of Cookies: 

  * "Session cookies", which allow websites to link the actions of a User during a browser session, and disappear when the User leaves the website;
  * "Permanent cookies", which remember the User's actions and preferences on a website, which remain in the User's terminal;
  * "First-party cookies", which are set in the website domain name listed in the address bar, and
  * "Third-party cookies", which are set by other domain sources that have items on the page.

Cookies enable us, for example, to enhance your online experience, facilitate electronic communications and measure online audience and traffic. Each browser of each individual Device has its own cookie settings and configuration options that can be managed:

  * For Internet Explorer: http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows7/how-to-manage-cookies-in-internet-explorer-9
  * For Chrome: https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en
  * For Firefox: http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer#w_cookie-settings

By using the Site and subscribing to the Services, you expressly consent to the use of Cookies in accordance with the United Kingdom's Data Protection Act.

## 8\. User's rights

We want our Users to enjoy their visit to our Site, and we respect their privacy. To this end, we provide numerous privacy choices. 

  * Right not to provide informationYou can choose not to provide us with any Personal Information, or not to respond to certain questions. However, if you wish to obtain access to certain content, ask us a question, ask for a Tradesman quote, or to take advantage of certain features of the Site, you may be required to provide certain contact or other Personal Information, as indicated in the relevant form. 
  * Right to access, right to modify, right to correct and right to delete Personal InformationIf you are a Registered User of the Site (Registered Consumer or Registered Tradesman), you may update or correct the information you provided to us by requesting us to make such changes as indicated in the "How to contact us" section. 
  * Right to block cookiesYou can choose to block cookies. To do so, please review the cookies and other technology section. Please note that if you disable all cookies from this Site, you will not be able to access certain portions of the Site 
  * Right to object to new uses of your Personal InformationIf at any time we wish to disclose or use your Personal Information in a way or for a purpose other than as described in this Privacy Notice, you will be given the opportunity to opt-out. 
  * Right to know about third party marketingWe do not currently share your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If at any time we wish to disclose, or use your personal data in a way, or for a purpose other than as described in this Privacy Notice, you will be given the opportunity to opt-out. 
  * Right to block marketing communicationsIf you no longer wish to receive marketing information or communications from us or from our affiliated entities, please send us an email as indicated in the "How to contact us" section. You can also unsubscribe from our distribution list by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communications that you receive from us. 
  * Right to block tailored advertisingYou can choose to block the use of tailored advertising about us on other websites, based on your visit to our Site by visiting the website of Network Advertising Initiative, that of the Digital Advertising Alliance, or similar websites that advertising networks offer for these purposes. 

Please note, however, that if you choose not to receive tailored advertisements, you will still see online advertisements, about us or other companies. In addition, any opt-out will apply only to the activities conducted with the specific browser that you used for opting out, and will not be limited to your use of the Site. 

  * Access RequestYou have the right to ask for a copy of the personal information we hold about you, which is called a "subject access request', for which we charge a fixed statutory fee of £10.00. 

## 9\. Security

We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, loss, misuse, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. While we do our best to implement security measures, we cannot guarantee the security of our Site and databases, nor can we guarantee that the Personal Information you submit to us on our Site will not be intercepted over the Internet. Moreover, we are not responsible for the actions of third parties. 

## 10\. Limitation of liability

We exercise reasonable efforts to safeguard the security and confidentiality of your Personal Information; however, transmissions protected by industry standard technology and administered by humans cannot be guaranteed to be secure. We will not be liable for unauthorized disclosure of personal data that occurs through no fault of ours including, but not limited to, errors in transmission, access to your account by anyone, uses of your User ID and password by a third party, your failure to comply with your security obligations, and the unauthorized acts of our employees. 

## 11\. Links to other websites

This Privacy Notice addresses only the use and disclosure of information that we collect from you through the Site or through our interaction with you. Our Site may contain links to other websites. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit Personal Information from you. They follow their own rules regarding the use or disclosure of the Personal Information you submit to them. We are not responsible for the actions of these other websites. We recommend that you read the privacy policies or statements of these other websites. 

## 12\. Our policy towards children

The Site is not directed to children, and we do not intentionally collect or maintain Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13 years old. If you become aware that a child or anyone under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us as indicated in the "How to contact us" section. 

## 13\. International transfer of information

Your information may be transferred, stored, maintained and processed within the European Economic Area (EEA). Any transfer of Personal Information will be in full compliance with all aspects of the United Kingdom's Data Protection Act. 

## 14\. Updates and modifications

We reserve the right in our sole discretion to update or modify this Privacy Notice at any time and you agree to be bound by such modifications or updates. Any of these material modifications or updates will be notified to you with the date of the change. Your continued use of the Site after being notified of these updates or modifications will constitute your agreement to these updates or modifications. We encourage you to review periodically this Privacy Notice in order to be informed about how we protect your Personal Information and to be aware of any update or modification. 

## 15\. Who controls your information

ServiceMagic Ltd. owns and operates the Site and controls the Information collected. ServiceMagic Ltd is formally registered under the United Kingdom's Data Protection Act to hold and use Personal Information, in accordance with the provisions of the Act. The registration number is 06303595 and is renewable annually. 

**© 2014** ServiceMagic, Ltd, All rights reserved
